Inventory of the Charles Francis Sloane papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Slides, 1955-1973 (Boxes 16-18)
  - 8. Vietnam, 1955-1959 (Box 16)
    1-6: Dalat market, Mont. bringing out of jungle; 8-13: Buddhist temple Saigon; 14: Pahi's traffic island; 17-18: En route to Cathuto; 19: Perfume rines-Hue; 21-32: First hunting trip with Chuck; 33-41: Saigon and Parade; 42-57: Montaguard Catholic Church Dalat; 58-64: Mont. village women weaving; 65-69: Ban me and hust, hunting with elephants; 70: Hunting Baotang, 3 Frontiers; 71-73: Mao tribeswoman, Dalat market; 74-76: Goat hunt; 77-88: Bear hunt; 89-100: Last visit to Mont. village for hunting.
  - 9. Vietnam, 1955-1959, Cambodia (Box 17)
    1-6: Montaguard bringing resin (liquid) out of jungle to sell to Viets; 8-13: Buddhist temple Saigon; 14: Pabies traffic Saigon, travelling outside of Saigon; 16: Harbor, bridge bombed; 17-18: En route to Cautho; 19: Perfume river Hue; 21-32: First hunting trip with Chuck; 33-41: Saigon and Parade crowds; 43-57: At Dalat and Montaguard Catholic Church; 59-64: Montaguard village women weaving; 65: Ban she short hunting; 69: Elephants; 70: Hunting Bantera 3 Frontier, Ban Me Ghuot Man Tribe; 76: Gaur hunt; 77-88: Bear hunt.
  - 10. I-Corps, 1962-1964 (Box 17)
    1: Military and mobile sandwich shops; Emperor's Palace, walled city; sawring planks; DMZ and Quang Tri Province; Phu Bai Compact; boats to new village; Hai Van Pass; Village Census Teams, Q. Tri Province; seven-storied Pagoda.
  - 11-12 skipped by numbering system
  - 13. I-Corps, 1962-1964; Tray 10; 1962-1964 North Central Lawlands Region, Huc and five provinces (Box 17)
    1-20: Travel via Helicopter with American military to ashon valley on border of Laos; 22-62: Emperors tombs, Ming Mang; 64-83: US Advisor effort showing how hamlet can defend itself. Helicopter comes to rescue, but not at night. At night village is alone.
  - 14. I-Corps, 1962-1964; 1962-1964: North Central Lowlands, here and 5 provinces (Box 17)
    1-5: Short visit to Ban Me Phuot; 6: Pleiku Airport; 7-15: French resort atop mountain overlooking China Sea; 16-20: Ceremony at Maag compound Hue re Assassen, of President Kennedy, Nov. 3 1963; 22-23: Trip to Qui Nhon; 24-30: Flight in area around Da Naag; 32-38: Trip so. of Da Naag to Confucian temple; 39-45: Quang Trinh province; 46-63: To Quang Ngai province; 65-85: Flying over VN; 86-94: Ngo Diah Can's weekend retreat, Thua Thien province, en route to Ta Anh beach.
  - 15. I-Corps and Saigon, Diem Coup, Nov. 1963; Nov. 1963, Ngo Dienh, Diem Coup, Saigon (Box 17)
    1-14; 15-26: Hue Ngo Dinh Banh's temple, was nearing completion, makeshift prison, etc.; 27-52: Cham Moreau Danang, marble mountain boy carving marble; 53-94: Trips to Khe Danh, on Laotian border visit Eugenia and Millers, Ora Moss; 95-100: Trip to Nam Dong, Thua Thien Province with Province Chief and Regional Police Director. One week later camp overrun by VC; Jerry Hicket was in camp during attack.
  - 16. Vietnam out of Saigon, 1964-1969 (Box 17)
    1-8: Visiting advisors in Provinces out of Saigon in Delta; 9-19: Walter going home party at tour Dan Nhut, late 1964; 21-44: Delta, last few back to Saigon (outskirts); 46-69: Visit to Cham Village without food for several weeks because occupied by VC, Phan Thiet Binh Thuan Provinces; 68-70: Children's leprosy colony; 70-75: En route to Phan rice harvest, Ninh Thuan Province on range at Phan Thiet; 77-80; 1969, 82-99: Viet Paintings and Viet Prophet Catholic Church.
  - 17. Vietnam, 1969-1973 (Box 17)
    1-33: Saigon, various; 35-45: 1969, April, 10-day trip to I-Corp Advisors, Quang Ngai, Steve Rimmer; 46-98: City of Hue showing damage by rioters, later VC, our old home and USIS, Consulate etc., RR bridge replaced by Pontoon bridge, last slide Province of Quang Tri.
  - 18-20 skipped by numbering system
  - 21. Vietnam Mekong Delta, 1971-1973 (Box 18)
    1-17: Viet Painting, Oriental Antiques, National Police Talent Center Saigon; 20-26: Trip to Pleiker; 27-35: 1992, takedurivist Saigon; 37-62: Back and forth to Cautho from Saigon and stationed there; 64-91: New Buddhist cult, starting in Cautho, temple next to my apt. house, 1st party-opening temple, American folk to stay indoors; 92-100: Antiques, Cautho.
  - 22. MACAD, 1959; Angkor Wat, 1958 (Box 18)
    1-46: With Geo and Mary Newman and 2 Girls from MSU/Vietnam; 48-100: Angkor Wat and Rundletts and Melv Handville, 1959.
  - 23. Karachi, 1957; Japan, 1957; Malaya and Singapore, 1958 (Box 18)
    1-16: Karachi 1957, enroute Home Leave; 18-38: Japan visiting fixes Yokahama, Imperial Palace Tokyo, enroute Vietnam, 1957 visits with Mr & Mrs Do Van Minh, Viet Consulate Officer; 40-78: Accompanied 3 high level Viet Police on Tour of Police, Malaya, Singapore and Thailand, 1958; 80-92: Viet Mgt Class, International Police Academy, at home, guests for dinner, '73.
  - 24. Vietnam, Washington, Tony Cistano, 1973 (Box 18)
    1-35: Viet artifacts, Tony Cistano, Washington 1973.
  - 25. East and West Pakistan, 1967-1968 (Box 18)
  - 26. Last Days in Vietnam, 1973 (Box 18)